{"id": "s001", "text": "Apple filed a patent infringement lawsuit against Samsung over touchscreen technology used in its Galaxy phones.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s002", "text": "Google won its antitrust appeal against the European Commission, overturning a record 2.4 billion euro fine.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "European Commission", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s003", "text": "Meta was ordered by the Irish Data Protection Commission to pay a 1.2 billion euro fine for violating GDPR rules on data transfers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Meta", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Irish Data Protection Commission", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s004", "text": "Oracle lost its decade-long copyright battle against Google over the use of Java APIs in Android.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Oracle", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s005", "text": "The FTC alleged that Microsoft engaged in anticompetitive practices by bundling Teams with its Office 365 suite.", "extractions": [{"entity": "FTC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s006", "text": "Qualcomm was subpoenaed by the DOJ as part of a broader investigation into chip licensing practices across the semiconductor industry.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Qualcomm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "DOJ", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s007", "text": "Amazon acquired MGM Studios for 8.45 billion dollars, gaining a vast library of films and television content.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "MGM Studios", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s008", "text": "Nvidia and TSMC announced a deepened partnership to co-develop next-generation Blackwell GPU fabrication at the 3nm process node.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s009", "text": "Intel lost its contract to supply processors for Apple's Mac lineup as Apple transitioned to its own in-house silicon chips.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s010", "text": "Apple canceled its decade-long autonomous vehicle project, redirecting thousands of engineers toward generative AI initiatives.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s011", "text": "SoftBank agreed to acquire Ampere Computing, a cloud-native chip designer, for 6.5 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "SoftBank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Ampere Computing", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s012", "text": "Ford and SK Innovation announced a joint venture to build three battery manufacturing plants across the United States.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Ford", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "SK Innovation", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s013", "text": "Tesla announced plans to build a new Gigafactory in Mexico, its first major manufacturing facility outside the United States and China.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s014", "text": "Pfizer reported that its mRNA cancer vaccine candidate achieved a 44 percent reduction in recurrence in late-stage trials.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Pfizer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s015", "text": "Tesla delivered 435,000 vehicles in Q3, missing analyst consensus of 463,000 and marking the second consecutive quarter of declining volumes.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s016", "text": "Nvidia reported revenue of 22.1 billion dollars, exceeding Wall Street estimates of 20.4 billion dollars on surging data center demand.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s017", "text": "Intel reported earnings in line with analyst expectations, with data center revenue flat and PC segment showing modest recovery.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s018", "text": "Google hired more than 30 senior AI researchers from OpenAI, offering compensation packages reportedly exceeding 10 million dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s019", "text": "Apple's chief design officer Jony Ive resigned to establish his own independent creative firm.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Jony Ive", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s020", "text": "Microsoft laid off 10,000 employees, roughly 5 percent of its global workforce, citing slowing cloud growth and economic uncertainty.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s021", "text": "Amazon Web Services lost its lead cloud contract with the US Department of Defense to Microsoft Azure in a reversal of an earlier award.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon Web Services", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Microsoft Azure", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s022", "text": "Novo Nordisk received FDA approval for its obesity drug Wegovy for cardiovascular risk reduction, expanding its approved patient population significantly.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Novo Nordisk", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "FDA", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s023", "text": "Boeing's 737 MAX was grounded globally by aviation regulators following two fatal crashes linked to software defects in the MCAS system.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Boeing", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s024", "text": "TSMC's production delays at its 3nm node forced Apple to push back its iPhone 16 Pro launch by approximately six weeks.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "iPhone 16 Pro", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s025", "text": "The US government imposed export restrictions on advanced AI chips, barring Nvidia from selling its H100 and A100 GPUs to Chinese customers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "US government", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Chinese customers", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s026", "text": "Apple lost several top AI researchers to Google and Meta amid its strict return-to-office policy at its Cupertino headquarters.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s027", "text": "Samsung filed for bankruptcy protection for its display panel subsidiary amid collapsing LCD prices and overcapacity in the market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s028", "text": "General Motors emerged from bankruptcy restructuring ahead of schedule, raising 23 billion dollars in its IPO.", "extractions": [{"entity": "General Motors", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s029", "text": "OpenAI launched GPT-5, claiming a 40 percent improvement in reasoning benchmarks over its predecessor.", "extractions": [{"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s030", "text": "Qualcomm was granted a patent for a new low-power 5G modem architecture that outperforms existing designs by a factor of three.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Qualcomm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s031", "text": "Eli Lilly and Novo Nordisk both reported stronger than expected sales of their GLP-1 drugs, with combined revenue surpassing analyst forecasts by 15 percent.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Eli Lilly", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Novo Nordisk", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s032", "text": "New Basel IV capital requirements forced major European banks including Deutsche Bank and BNP Paribas to raise additional tier-one capital buffers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Deutsche Bank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "BNP Paribas", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Basel IV regulators", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s033", "text": "Waymo, Alphabet's autonomous vehicle subsidiary, launched a paid robotaxi service in San Francisco following regulatory approval.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Waymo", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Alphabet", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s034", "text": "ASML reported record order intake of 9 billion euros for its next-generation EUV lithography machines, driven by demand from TSMC and Samsung.", "extractions": [{"entity": "ASML", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s035", "text": "Broadcom completed its acquisition of VMware for 69 billion dollars after receiving final regulatory approval from the European Union.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Broadcom", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "VMware", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "European Union", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s036", "text": "Arm Holdings priced its IPO at 51 dollars per share, raising 4.87 billion dollars in the largest technology listing of the year.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Arm Holdings", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s037", "text": "Johnson and Johnson agreed to pay 8.9 billion dollars to settle tens of thousands of lawsuits alleging its talc-based baby powder caused cancer.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Johnson and Johnson", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s038", "text": "Alphabet announced a 70 billion dollar share buyback program and initiated its first ever quarterly dividend of 20 cents per share.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Alphabet", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s039", "text": "Rivian secured a 5 billion dollar investment from Volkswagen in exchange for a joint venture to co-develop next-generation EV software platforms.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Rivian", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Volkswagen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s040", "text": "TSMC warned that geopolitical tensions over Taiwan could disrupt its chip supply to global customers including Apple, Nvidia, and AMD.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s041", "text": "Stripe poached PayPal's head of enterprise sales along with a team of five senior account executives.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Stripe", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "PayPal", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s042", "text": "OpenAI's chief scientist Ilya Sutskever resigned to found his own AI safety startup.", "extractions": [{"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Ilya Sutskever", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s043", "text": "Meta hired more than 100 engineers from Twitter following Elon Musk's mass layoffs at the social media platform.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Meta", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Twitter", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s044", "text": "Goldman Sachs promoted a record number of managing directors this cycle, signaling confidence in its dealmaking pipeline.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Goldman Sachs", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s045", "text": "Boeing's CEO Dave Calhoun announced his resignation amid ongoing safety and production crises at the aircraft manufacturer.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Boeing", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Dave Calhoun", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s046", "text": "Salesforce lost its co-CEO Bret Taylor to a new venture, leaving Marc Benioff as sole chief executive.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Salesforce", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Bret Taylor", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s047", "text": "Apple rehired several former chip engineers from Intel's failed mobile division to bolster its silicon design team.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s048", "text": "Zoom laid off 1,300 employees, roughly 15 percent of its workforce, as pandemic-era growth reversed sharply.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Zoom", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s049", "text": "Google DeepMind unveiled Gemini Ultra, claiming it surpassed GPT-4 on all major academic benchmarks.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Google DeepMind", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Gemini Ultra", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s050", "text": "Samsung launched its Galaxy S25 lineup featuring its first fully in-house developed mobile processor.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Galaxy S25", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s051", "text": "Microsoft released Copilot for Microsoft 365, integrating GPT-4 across Word, Excel, and Teams for enterprise customers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Copilot", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s052", "text": "Tesla unveiled its long-awaited Robotaxi, a fully autonomous vehicle with no steering wheel or pedals.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s053", "text": "Anthropic released Claude 3 Opus, which outperformed GPT-4 on reasoning and coding benchmarks according to internal evaluations.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Anthropic", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Claude 3 Opus", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s054", "text": "Rivian recalled all 13,000 of its delivered vehicles due to a loose fastener that could cause drivers to lose steering control.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Rivian", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s055", "text": "AMD patented a new chiplet interconnect architecture that significantly reduces latency between compute dies.", "extractions": [{"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s056", "text": "Party City filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection after failing to secure additional financing from lenders.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Party City", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s057", "text": "WeWork filed for bankruptcy, marking a dramatic collapse for a company once valued at 47 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "WeWork", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s058", "text": "Hertz emerged from bankruptcy with a restructured balance sheet and a new fleet strategy focused on electric vehicles.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Hertz", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s059", "text": "Celsius Network filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy, freezing withdrawals for more than 1.7 million customers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Celsius Network", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}, {"entity": "customers", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s060", "text": "Sears emerged from bankruptcy for the second time in three years, raising doubts about the viability of its turnaround plan.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Sears", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s061", "text": "Apple's App Store generated 1.1 trillion dollars in developer billings and sales in 2023, according to an independent study commissioned by Apple.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s062", "text": "Snap reported a 39 percent decline in revenue as advertisers shifted budgets toward TikTok and Instagram Reels.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Snap", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "TikTok", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Instagram", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s063", "text": "TSMC reported record quarterly profit of 9.2 billion dollars, driven by surging demand for AI chips from Nvidia and Apple.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s064", "text": "Disney's streaming segment turned profitable for the first time, offsetting continued weakness in its linear television business.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Disney", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s065", "text": "Alibaba missed revenue estimates for the third consecutive quarter as domestic consumption in China remained sluggish.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Alibaba", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s066", "text": "JPMorgan Chase reported record full-year profit of 49.6 billion dollars, driven by higher interest rates boosting net interest income.", "extractions": [{"entity": "JPMorgan Chase", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s067", "text": "Airbnb reported its first ever full-year profit, generating 1.9 billion dollars in net income on revenue of 8.4 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Airbnb", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s068", "text": "Credit Suisse reported a full-year loss of 7.3 billion Swiss francs as client outflows accelerated amid confidence crisis.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Credit Suisse", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s069", "text": "The DOJ indicted former Theranos CEO Elizabeth Holmes on federal wire fraud charges related to deception of investors and patients.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Elizabeth Holmes", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Theranos", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s070", "text": "Binance pleaded guilty to money laundering violations and agreed to pay 4.3 billion dollars in penalties to US regulators.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Binance", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s071", "text": "Epic Games won its antitrust case against Google, with a jury finding that Google illegally monopolized the Android app distribution market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Epic Games", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s072", "text": "The SEC charged Coinbase with operating an unregistered securities exchange, threatening its core business model.", "extractions": [{"entity": "SEC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Coinbase", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s073", "text": "Exxon Mobil won its lawsuit against activist shareholders who had pushed for binding climate resolutions at its annual meeting.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Exxon Mobil", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "activist shareholders", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s074", "text": "Apple and Google were both named in a class action lawsuit alleging their app store duopoly artificially inflated prices for consumers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s075", "text": "Pfizer acquired Seagen for 43 billion dollars, gaining access to its antibody-drug conjugate cancer therapy pipeline.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Pfizer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Seagen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s076", "text": "Disney sold its stake in Vice Media as part of a broader retreat from digital media investments made during the streaming boom.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Disney", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Vice Media", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s077", "text": "Microsoft and Mistral AI announced a partnership giving Microsoft exclusive rights to distribute Mistral's large language models via Azure.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Mistral AI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s078", "text": "Sony acquired Bungie, the game studio behind Destiny, for 3.6 billion dollars to bolster its PlayStation live service portfolio.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Sony", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Bungie", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s079", "text": "Amazon shut down its Amazon Care telehealth service just two years after launching it to employees and external customers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s080", "text": "Volkswagen announced it would close three factories in Germany and cut tens of thousands of jobs as EV demand fell short of targets.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Volkswagen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s081", "text": "Netflix and Microsoft announced a partnership to launch an ad-supported subscription tier, with Microsoft handling ad sales technology.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Netflix", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s082", "text": "Qualcomm acquired Nuvia, a chip startup founded by former Apple silicon engineers, for 1.4 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Qualcomm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Nuvia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s083", "text": "Google terminated its contract with a defense contractor after employee protests over Project Nimbus, an AI contract with the Israeli government.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s084", "text": "Lyft sold its autonomous vehicle division Level 5 to Toyota's Woven Planet subsidiary for 550 million dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Lyft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Toyota", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s085", "text": "Also weighing on markets was concern over Nvidia's export curbs. Its H100 chips are now banned from sale in China, hitting its data center revenue outlook, while AMD said its MI300 sales could also be affected by the restrictions.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "H100", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "MI300", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s086", "text": "Investors cheered as Microsoft reported strong Azure growth of 29 percent. But its shares gave back some gains after the company warned that capital expenditure would rise significantly in the coming quarters to fund AI infrastructure.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Azure", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s087", "text": "Apple's iPhone sales in China fell 19 percent in the first quarter as Huawei's Mate 60 series gained significant market share following its surprise launch.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "iPhone", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Huawei", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Mate 60", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s088", "text": "Shares of ASML dropped sharply after the Dutch government revoked its export license for chipmaking equipment to China, following pressure from the US.", "extractions": [{"entity": "ASML", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Dutch government", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s089", "text": "SoftBank's Vision Fund posted a 32 billion dollar loss for the fiscal year, its worst performance since inception, dragged down by writedowns on WeWork and other portfolio companies.", "extractions": [{"entity": "SoftBank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Vision Fund", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "WeWork", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s090", "text": "Shares of Eli Lilly surged after its experimental Alzheimer's drug donanemab significantly slowed cognitive decline in a late-stage trial, while rival Biogen's shares fell as investors rotated out of its approved treatment Leqembi.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Eli Lilly", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "donanemab", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Biogen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Leqembi", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s091", "text": "JPMorgan agreed to acquire First Republic Bank after US regulators seized the failed lender, marking the second largest bank failure in American history.", "extractions": [{"entity": "JPMorgan", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "First Republic Bank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s092", "text": "UBS was forced by Swiss regulators to acquire Credit Suisse for 3 billion Swiss francs in an emergency rescue deal over a single weekend.", "extractions": [{"entity": "UBS", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Credit Suisse", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}, {"entity": "Swiss regulators", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s093", "text": "Broadcom shares rose after it reported that its AI chip revenue had tripled year over year, driven by custom silicon orders from Google and Meta.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Broadcom", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Meta", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s094", "text": "Spotify announced it was raising subscription prices for the second time in a year across all markets, citing rising content and royalty costs.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Spotify", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s095", "text": "Tesla cut prices on its entire vehicle lineup for the fourth time this year, raising fears of a broader EV price war that could hurt margins across the industry.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s096", "text": "ARM Holdings saw its shares double within days of its Nasdaq IPO, making it the most successful semiconductor listing in over a decade.", "extractions": [{"entity": "ARM Holdings", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s097", "text": "Instacart priced its IPO below its initial target range amid weak investor appetite, raising 660 million dollars at a valuation far below its pandemic-era peak.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Instacart", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s098", "text": "AMD's shares fell after it announced the acquisition of server maker ZT Systems for 4.9 billion dollars, with analysts questioning whether the price was justified.", "extractions": [{"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "ZT Systems", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s099", "text": "Xiaomi received regulatory approval to begin selling its first electric vehicle in China, entering a market dominated by BYD and Tesla.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Xiaomi", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "BYD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s100", "text": "Concerns mounted over the semiconductor supply chain after an earthquake in Taiwan disrupted operations at several TSMC facilities, sending shares of Apple, Nvidia, and AMD lower.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s101", "text": "Bank of America reported stronger than expected earnings, with net interest income rising 8 percent as the lender benefited from higher rates.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Bank of America", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s102", "text": "Johnson and Johnson lost its appeal against a 2.1 billion dollar talc verdict, dealing a major blow to the healthcare giant's legal strategy.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Johnson and Johnson", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s103", "text": "General Motors announced it would halt production at its Orion Assembly plant in Michigan, citing weak demand for its electric pickup trucks.", "extractions": [{"entity": "General Motors", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s104", "text": "Berkshire Hathaway increased its stake in Occidental Petroleum to 28 percent, fueling speculation that Warren Buffett may pursue a full takeover.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Berkshire Hathaway", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Occidental Petroleum", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s105", "text": "Morgan Stanley upgraded its outlook for Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, citing accelerating orders from artificial intelligence chip designers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s106", "text": "The New York Times filed a copyright lawsuit against Microsoft and OpenAI, alleging that millions of its articles were used to train large language models without permission.", "extractions": [{"entity": "The New York Times", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s107", "text": "Wells Fargo agreed to pay 3.7 billion dollars to settle charges by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau over widespread mismanagement of customer accounts.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Wells Fargo", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Consumer Financial Protection Bureau", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s108", "text": "Procter and Gamble raised its full-year earnings forecast after posting better than expected quarterly results driven by price increases across its consumer brands.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Procter and Gamble", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s109", "text": "Lockheed Martin won a 17 billion dollar contract from the US Department of Defense to supply F-35 fighter jets over the next five years.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Lockheed Martin", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "US Department of Defense", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s110", "text": "Bristol Myers Squibb acquired Karuna Therapeutics for 14 billion dollars, gaining access to its pipeline of neuropsychiatric drug candidates.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Bristol Myers Squibb", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Karuna Therapeutics", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s111", "text": "The chipmaker posted record quarterly sales, driven by insatiable demand for its artificial intelligence accelerators from cloud computing giants.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the chipmaker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s112", "text": "The e-commerce giant slashed its workforce by 18,000 employees, the largest layoff in the company's history, as it pulled back from pandemic-era expansion.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the e-commerce giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s113", "text": "The Cupertino company faced fresh regulatory scrutiny in Europe after the bloc ruled that its App Store payment practices violated digital markets rules.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Cupertino company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s114", "text": "The Redmond software giant reported that its cloud division grew 29 percent year over year, beating analyst estimates for the sixth consecutive quarter.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Redmond software giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s115", "text": "The electric vehicle maker cut prices on its best-selling sedan by 2,000 dollars, intensifying a price war with legacy automakers entering the EV market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the electric vehicle maker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s116", "text": "The search giant agreed to pay 1.4 billion dollars to settle biometric data privacy claims brought by the state of Texas.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the search giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s117", "text": "The social media company announced it would begin charging users eight dollars per month for its verification badge, reversing years of offering the feature for free.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the social media company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s118", "text": "Advanced Micro Devices reported its data center revenue surpassed 2.3 billion dollars for the first time, driven by strong adoption of its AI accelerator chips.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Advanced Micro Devices", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s119", "text": "International Business Machines beat earnings estimates as its consulting division returned to growth following a period of client spending caution.", "extractions": [{"entity": "International Business Machines", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s120", "text": "Taiwan Semiconductor warned that geopolitical risks could force it to accelerate overseas factory construction at significantly higher cost than domestic operations.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Taiwan Semiconductor", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s121", "text": "JPMorgan's Jamie Dimon warned of stagflation risks in his annual shareholder letter, sending shares of major US banks lower.", "extractions": [{"entity": "JPMorgan", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Jamie Dimon", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "0", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s122", "text": "Elon Musk's acquisition of Twitter, later rebranded as X, was completed at 44 billion dollars, a price widely seen as significantly above market value.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Elon Musk", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Twitter", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s123", "text": "Sam Altman was reinstated as OpenAI's chief executive just days after being abruptly fired by the board, following a revolt by staff and investors.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Sam Altman", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s124", "text": "Nvidia's Jensen Huang unveiled the company's next-generation Blackwell architecture at GTC, sending the stock up 7 percent in after-hours trading.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Jensen Huang", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s125", "text": "Apple's Tim Cook testified before Congress defending the company's App Store policies, denying that Apple held a monopoly over iPhone software distribution.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Tim Cook", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s126", "text": "BofA upgraded Tesla to buy from neutral, citing improving margins and the upcoming launch of its affordable vehicle model.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s127", "text": "MS raised its price target on NVDA to 1,100 dollars, calling it the primary beneficiary of the AI infrastructure spending cycle.", "extractions": [{"entity": "NVDA", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s128", "text": "GOOG shares fell after reports emerged that Apple was considering replacing its default search engine with an AI-powered alternative.", "extractions": [{"entity": "GOOG", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s129", "text": "TSLA delivered fewer vehicles than expected in Q2, missing the Street by 5 percent, while BYD overtook it as the world's top EV seller.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSLA", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "BYD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s130", "text": "AMZN beat on both revenue and earnings per share, with AWS growing 17 percent year over year and advertising revenue accelerating to 12.1 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "AMZN", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "AWS", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s131", "text": "Shares of the Dutch chip equipment maker fell sharply after Washington pressured the Netherlands to restrict exports of its most advanced lithography machines to China.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Dutch chip equipment maker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s132", "text": "The Japanese automaker recalled 1.4 million vehicles in North America over a defect in the fuel pump that could cause sudden engine stalls.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Japanese automaker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s133", "text": "The South Korean battery maker secured a 7 billion dollar supply agreement with a major US electric vehicle manufacturer to supply next-generation lithium iron phosphate cells.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the South Korean battery maker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a major US electric vehicle manufacturer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s134", "text": "The German automaker said it would invest 30 billion euros in electric vehicle development over the next five years, doubling its previous commitment.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the German automaker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s135", "text": "The streaming giant lost 1.2 million subscribers in North America, its first quarterly decline in over a decade, sending its shares down 35 percent.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the streaming giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s136", "text": "The ride-hailing company posted its first ever quarterly profit on an adjusted basis, a milestone that sent its shares up 9 percent in after-hours trading.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the ride-hailing company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s137", "text": "Also under pressure was the payments processor, whose shares dropped after it revealed that fraud losses had exceeded internal targets for the third consecutive quarter.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the payments processor", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s138", "text": "The drugmaker's shares surged after its experimental weight loss pill showed results comparable to injectable GLP-1 therapies in a mid-stage clinical trial.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the drugmaker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s139", "text": "Shares of the semiconductor equipment company dropped after its largest customer announced plans to delay its next fabrication plant by eighteen months.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the semiconductor equipment company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "its largest customer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s140", "text": "The Chinese tech giant was added to the US Entity List, barring American companies from supplying it with components or software without a government license.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Chinese tech giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s141", "text": "Shares of Moderna fell after its rival reported positive Phase 3 data for an mRNA flu vaccine, raising fears of increased competition in the respiratory vaccine market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Moderna", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its rival", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s142", "text": "Palantir won a 480 million dollar contract from the US Army to expand its battlefield AI software across active combat units.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Palantir", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "US Army", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s143", "text": "Block, formerly known as Square, reported that its Cash App monthly active users declined for the first time since the product launched.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Block", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Cash App", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s144", "text": "Meta Platforms, the parent company of Facebook and Instagram, reported advertising revenue grew 27 percent as its AI-driven feed recommendations improved engagement.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Meta Platforms", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s145", "text": "Alphabet Inc posted revenue of 86.3 billion dollars, beating consensus by 3 percent, as Google Search held its dominant position despite rising competition from AI chatbots.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Alphabet Inc", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Google Search", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s146", "text": "NVidia, the AI chip darling, saw its market capitalization briefly surpass three trillion dollars, overtaking Microsoft as the world's most valuable company.", "extractions": [{"entity": "NVidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s147", "text": "Apple Inc's services revenue reached an all-time high of 23.9 billion dollars, growing 14 percent year over year and accounting for a rising share of total company profits.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple Inc", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s148", "text": "Amazon.com reported that its advertising business surpassed 14 billion dollars in quarterly revenue for the first time, growing faster than both Google and Meta's ad units.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon.com", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Meta", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s149", "text": "Shares of ASML Holding fell after management warned that customer order cancellations in China could reduce its 2024 revenue guidance by up to 10 percent.", "extractions": [{"entity": "ASML Holding", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s150", "text": "Novo Nordisk A/S overtook LVMH as Europe's most valuable listed company, driven by surging demand for its obesity and diabetes treatments.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Novo Nordisk A/S", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "LVMH", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s151", "text": "The maker of the world's most advanced chip manufacturing equipment said customer demand remained robust despite ongoing trade restrictions between the US and China.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the maker of the world's most advanced chip manufacturing equipment", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s152", "text": "Buffett's conglomerate disclosed a new stake in a major Japanese trading house, sending the latter's shares to a multi-decade high in Tokyo trading.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Buffett's conglomerate", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a major Japanese trading house", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s153", "text": "Musk's rocket company successfully landed its Super Heavy booster for the first time, a milestone that analysts said could dramatically reduce launch costs.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Musk's rocket company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s154", "text": "Cook's company was fined 1.8 billion euros by European regulators for restricting music streaming rivals from informing users about cheaper subscription options.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Cook's company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s155", "text": "Zuckerberg's social network reported its daily active users crossed three billion for the first time, cementing its position as the world's largest social platform.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Zuckerberg's social network", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s156", "text": "The iPhone maker and the search giant jointly face an antitrust probe over their revenue sharing agreement that makes Google the default search engine on Apple devices.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the iPhone maker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "the search giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s157", "text": "The chip designer and the foundry announced they would jointly develop a custom server processor for a major hyperscaler, combining design expertise with leading-edge manufacturing.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the chip designer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the foundry", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a major hyperscaler", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s158", "text": "The ride-hailing giant and the food delivery company announced a merger that would create a combined entity valued at over 50 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the ride-hailing giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the food delivery company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s159", "text": "The biotech and the pharmaceutical giant announced positive Phase 3 results for their jointly developed cancer immunotherapy, sending both companies' shares sharply higher.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the biotech", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "the pharmaceutical giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s160", "text": "The payment network and the regional bank terminated their co-branded credit card partnership after a decade, with the bank switching to a competing card network.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the payment network", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the regional bank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a competing card network", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s161", "text": "Nvidia and AMD both warned that new US export restrictions on AI chips would materially impact their China revenue in the coming quarters.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s162", "text": "Apple and Google face a landmark antitrust trial over their search default agreement, with the DOJ arguing the deal illegally entrenched Google's dominance.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "DOJ", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s163", "text": "Tesla and BYD both reported record quarterly deliveries, signaling that global EV demand remained robust despite macroeconomic headwinds.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Tesla", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "BYD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s164", "text": "Microsoft and Google each announced billion-dollar AI infrastructure investments in Southeast Asia on the same day, intensifying their rivalry for cloud market share in the region.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s165", "text": "Pfizer and Moderna both reported declining revenue as demand for their Covid vaccines continued to normalize following the end of the pandemic emergency.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Pfizer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Moderna", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s166", "text": "Samsung and SK Hynix reported sharply higher memory chip profits as AI server demand drove a sustained recovery in DRAM and NAND pricing.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "SK Hynix", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "DRAM", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "NAND", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s167", "text": "JPMorgan and Goldman Sachs both posted record investment banking fees as the mergers and acquisitions market rebounded strongly from a two-year drought.", "extractions": [{"entity": "JPMorgan", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Goldman Sachs", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s168", "text": "Airbus overtook Boeing as the world's largest aircraft manufacturer by deliveries for the fifth consecutive year, as Boeing continued to struggle with production and safety issues.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Airbus", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Boeing", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s169", "text": "Spotify gained subscribers at the expense of Apple Music and Amazon Music as its AI-powered playlist feature drove a surge in user engagement.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Spotify", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Apple Music", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Amazon Music", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s170", "text": "Visa and Mastercard agreed to cap interchange fees for five years as part of a 30 billion dollar settlement with US merchants.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Visa", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Mastercard", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s171", "text": "Intel lost market share to both AMD and Arm-based processors in the server market, with its data center division posting its third consecutive quarterly decline.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "AMD", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Arm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s172", "text": "Netflix gained subscribers in every region while Disney Plus and Paramount Plus both reported net subscriber losses in their latest quarterly results.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Netflix", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Disney Plus", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Paramount Plus", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s173", "text": "TSMC raised its capital expenditure forecast while Samsung cut its chip investment budget, widening the technology gap between the two foundries.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s174", "text": "Uber gained significant market share from Lyft in major US cities after launching its new loyalty program, with Lyft acknowledging the competitive pressure in its earnings call.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Uber", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Lyft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s175", "text": "Shell and BP both reported weaker earnings as oil prices fell below 80 dollars a barrel, while TotalEnergies outperformed peers on stronger refining margins.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Shell", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "BP", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "TotalEnergies", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s176", "text": "Amazon Web Services lost cloud market share to Microsoft Azure for the second consecutive quarter, according to data from Synergy Research Group.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon Web Services", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Microsoft Azure", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s177", "text": "The semiconductor giant reported that its foundry division continued to bleed cash, losing 7 billion dollars in the first half of the year as it struggled to attract customers away from TSMC.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the semiconductor giant", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s178", "text": "The luxury goods conglomerate reported slowing sales in China as consumer confidence weakened, while its rival posted double-digit growth in the same market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the luxury goods conglomerate", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its rival", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s179", "text": "The activist hedge fund disclosed a 1.9 billion dollar stake in the consumer goods company and immediately called for the spin-off of its underperforming personal care division.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the activist hedge fund", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the consumer goods company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s180", "text": "The index provider announced it would remove the Chinese property developer from its benchmark indices following the company's failure to make coupon payments on offshore bonds.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the index provider", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the Chinese property developer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Bankruptcy"}]}
{"id": "s181", "text": "Concerns over Apple's growth outlook deepened after its largest contract manufacturer warned of weaker than expected orders for the upcoming iPhone cycle.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its largest contract manufacturer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s182", "text": "Nvidia's dominance in AI training chips came under threat after Google announced its sixth-generation tensor processing unit delivered three times the performance per watt.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "tensor processing unit", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s184", "text": "Meta's advertising revenue recovery surprised analysts as its Advantage Plus AI ad targeting system significantly outperformed manual campaign optimization for retail clients.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Meta", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Advantage Plus", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s185", "text": "Amazon's pharmacy business gained ground on CVS Health and Walgreens after it expanded same-day prescription delivery to 20 additional US cities.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Amazon", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "CVS Health", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Walgreens", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s186", "text": "Salesforce shares dropped after its chief operating officer resigned unexpectedly, the third C-suite departure at the software company in eighteen months.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Salesforce", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s187", "text": "OpenAI hired Fidji Simo, former CEO of Instacart, as its new head of applications, signaling a push toward commercializing its consumer products.", "extractions": [{"entity": "OpenAI", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Fidji Simo", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Instacart", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s188", "text": "Anthropic appointed a former Google DeepMind research director as its new chief scientist, strengthening its technical leadership ahead of a major funding round.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Anthropic", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Google DeepMind", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s189", "text": "Disney named a former Netflix executive as president of its streaming division, tasked with reversing subscriber losses and improving content return on investment.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Disney", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Netflix", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s190", "text": "Citigroup laid off 20,000 employees as part of its largest restructuring in decades under new CEO Jane Fraser, who pledged to simplify the bank's complex organizational structure.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Citigroup", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Jane Fraser", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "0", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s191", "text": "PayPal hired Alex Chriss from Intuit as its new chief executive, replacing Dan Schulman who retired after a decade leading the payments company.", "extractions": [{"entity": "PayPal", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Alex Chriss", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Intuit", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Dan Schulman", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "0", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s192", "text": "The Federal Reserve fined Deutsche Bank 186 million dollars for failing to fix longstanding deficiencies in its anti-money laundering controls.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Federal Reserve", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Deutsche Bank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s193", "text": "The European Commission approved Microsoft's acquisition of Activision Blizzard subject to conditions, overruling the UK's Competition and Markets Authority which had blocked the deal.", "extractions": [{"entity": "European Commission", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Activision Blizzard", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "UK Competition and Markets Authority", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s195", "text": "The SEC dropped its lawsuit against Ripple Labs, a partial victory for the crypto company which had fought the regulator for four years over whether XRP was an unregistered security.", "extractions": [{"entity": "SEC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Ripple Labs", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "XRP", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s196", "text": "Boeing's 737 MAX 9 was grounded by the FAA after a door plug blew out mid-flight on an Alaska Airlines jet, exposing a manufacturing quality crisis at the planemaker.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Boeing", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "FAA", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Alaska Airlines", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "737 MAX 9", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s197", "text": "Alphabet's self-driving unit Waymo was cleared by California regulators to expand its paid robotaxi service to all of San Francisco, dealing a blow to rival Cruise which had its license suspended.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Alphabet", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Waymo", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Cruise", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s198", "text": "Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company announced it would build a second chip factory in Arizona after receiving 6.6 billion dollars in grants from the US CHIPS Act.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "US CHIPS Act", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s199", "text": "Intel received 8.5 billion dollars in direct funding under the CHIPS Act to build semiconductor fabrication plants in Ohio, Arizona, and New Mexico.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "CHIPS Act", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "0", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s200", "text": "SoftBank's Vision Fund posted its first quarterly profit in two years as the valuations of its technology portfolio companies recovered alongside rising public markets.", "extractions": [{"entity": "SoftBank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Vision Fund", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s201", "text": "Uber Technologies reported its first ever annual operating profit, a milestone that chief executive Dara Khosrowshahi called a turning point for the company.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Uber Technologies", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Dara Khosrowshahi", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s202", "text": "Peloton reported its eighth consecutive quarterly revenue decline as pandemic-era demand for its connected fitness equipment continued to unwind.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Peloton", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s203", "text": "Block reported that Cash App gross profit grew 21 percent year over year, offsetting weakness in its Square merchant services division.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Block", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Cash App", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Square", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s204", "text": "Shopify beat revenue estimates after its merchant solutions segment accelerated, helped by market share gains from WooCommerce and Magento.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Shopify", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "WooCommerce", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Magento", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s205", "text": "Palantir's commercial revenue grew 55 percent driven by demand for its AIP artificial intelligence platform, with the company raising full-year guidance for the third consecutive quarter.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Palantir", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "AIP", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s206", "text": "Snowflake disappointed investors with weaker than expected product revenue growth, as competition from Databricks and cloud-native data warehouses intensified.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Snowflake", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Databricks", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s207", "text": "Arm Holdings reported royalty revenue grew 37 percent as its v9 architecture gained rapid adoption among smartphone and data center chip designers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Arm Holdings", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s208", "text": "Qualcomm beat earnings estimates and raised guidance after securing new design wins at Samsung for its Snapdragon processors, reversing earlier losses to Samsung's in-house Exynos chips.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Qualcomm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Samsung", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Snapdragon", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Exynos", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s209", "text": "Texas Instruments warned of a prolonged semiconductor downturn in industrial and automotive markets, sending shares of peers including Microchip Technology and ON Semiconductor sharply lower.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Texas Instruments", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Microchip Technology", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "ON Semiconductor", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s210", "text": "Applied Materials reported record backlog as chipmakers accelerated investment in advanced packaging technology to meet AI chip demand.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Applied Materials", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s211", "text": "Micron Technology forecast stronger than expected revenue for the next quarter, driven by high bandwidth memory orders from Nvidia for its Blackwell GPU systems.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Micron Technology", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Blackwell", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s212", "text": "Western Digital and Seagate both cut their quarterly dividends as hard disk drive demand collapsed faster than anticipated due to the shift to solid state storage.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Western Digital", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Seagate", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s213", "text": "Lam Research warned that export controls on semiconductor equipment sales to China would reduce its annual revenue by approximately 2 billion dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Lam Research", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s214", "text": "KLA Corporation raised its dividend and announced a 2 billion dollar share buyback after posting record quarterly earnings from its process control equipment division.", "extractions": [{"entity": "KLA Corporation", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s215", "text": "Broadcom's VMware integration exceeded management expectations, with cross-selling of networking software to existing VMware customers accelerating faster than the acquisition model assumed.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Broadcom", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "VMware", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s216", "text": "Workday lost its largest federal government contract to Oracle after a competitive rebid, representing approximately 300 million dollars in annual recurring revenue.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Workday", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Oracle", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s217", "text": "ServiceNow raised full-year guidance after its Now Assist AI features drove faster enterprise deal closures and higher average contract values than the prior year.", "extractions": [{"entity": "ServiceNow", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Now Assist", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s218", "text": "CrowdStrike faced significant customer backlash and potential legal liability after a faulty software update caused a global IT outage affecting 8.5 million Windows devices.", "extractions": [{"entity": "CrowdStrike", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "NewsRelease"}, {"entity": "Windows", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s219", "text": "Palo Alto Networks cut its billings forecast, triggering a broad selloff in cybersecurity stocks including CrowdStrike, Fortinet, and Zscaler.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Palo Alto Networks", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "CrowdStrike", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Fortinet", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Zscaler", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s220", "text": "Cloudflare signed its largest ever enterprise contract, a multi-year deal with a major financial institution worth over 100 million dollars.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Cloudflare", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a major financial institution", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s221", "text": "Johnson Controls agreed to sell its residential and light commercial HVAC business to Bosch for 8.1 billion dollars as part of a broader portfolio simplification strategy.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Johnson Controls", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Bosch", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s222", "text": "Honeywell International announced it would spin off its advanced materials division into a separate publicly traded company to unlock shareholder value.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Honeywell International", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s223", "text": "General Electric completed its three-way breakup, with GE Aerospace, GE Vernova, and GE HealthCare all trading as independent companies.", "extractions": [{"entity": "General Electric", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "GE Aerospace", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "GE Vernova", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "GE HealthCare", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s224", "text": "3M agreed to pay 10.3 billion dollars to settle claims that its Combat Arms earplugs caused hearing damage to hundreds of thousands of US military veterans.", "extractions": [{"entity": "3M", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s225", "text": "Caterpillar beat earnings estimates as infrastructure spending in North America and the Middle East offset weakness in its mining equipment segment in China.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Caterpillar", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s226", "text": "Deere and Company cut its full-year profit forecast for the second time as farmers delayed equipment purchases amid falling crop prices and high interest rates.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Deere and Company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s227", "text": "United Parcel Service lost its largest customer FedEx to a rival logistics network, costing it approximately 1.5 billion dollars in annual revenue.", "extractions": [{"entity": "United Parcel Service", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "FedEx", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s228", "text": "Delta Air Lines upgraded its full-year profit outlook as business travel demand recovered to pre-pandemic levels and fuel costs declined more than expected.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Delta Air Lines", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s229", "text": "Southwest Airlines faced pressure from activist investor Elliott Management, which disclosed a 1.9 billion dollar stake and demanded a change in leadership.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Southwest Airlines", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Elliott Management", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s230", "text": "American Airlines cut its revenue forecast after its decision to reduce reliance on travel agents backfired, causing a sharp drop in corporate bookings.", "extractions": [{"entity": "American Airlines", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s231", "text": "Novo Nordisk's obesity drug Wegovy faced a new challenger as Eli Lilly's tirzepatide showed superior weight loss results in a head-to-head clinical trial.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Novo Nordisk", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Wegovy", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Eli Lilly", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "tirzepatide", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s232", "text": "AstraZeneca voluntarily withdrew its Covid vaccine from global markets, citing a rare side effect that caused blood clotting in a small number of recipients.", "extractions": [{"entity": "AstraZeneca", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "NewsRelease"}]}
{"id": "s233", "text": "Merck won a key patent dispute against Moderna over mRNA technology used in Covid vaccines, potentially entitling it to royalties on billions of dollars in future sales.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Merck", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Moderna", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s234", "text": "AbbVie acquired ImmunoGen for 10.1 billion dollars to bolster its oncology pipeline ahead of the expiration of its blockbuster drug Humira's patent protection.", "extractions": [{"entity": "AbbVie", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "ImmunoGen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Humira", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s235", "text": "Regeneron and Sanofi reported that their jointly developed drug Dupixent crossed 10 billion dollars in annual sales for the first time, becoming one of the world's best-selling medicines.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Regeneron", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Sanofi", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Dupixent", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s236", "text": "Exxon Mobil completed its 60 billion dollar acquisition of Pioneer Natural Resources, creating the largest oil producer in the Permian Basin.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Exxon Mobil", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Pioneer Natural Resources", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s237", "text": "Chevron's acquisition of Hess was delayed after Exxon Mobil filed for arbitration claiming a right of first refusal over Hess's stake in a lucrative Guyana oilfield.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Chevron", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Hess", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Exxon Mobil", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s238", "text": "Saudi Aramco reported a 25 percent drop in annual profit as OPEC production cuts reduced its output while global oil prices remained under pressure.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Saudi Aramco", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "OPEC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s239", "text": "NextEra Energy raised its long-term earnings growth forecast after securing a record number of power purchase agreements for its renewable energy projects.", "extractions": [{"entity": "NextEra Energy", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s240", "text": "Enphase Energy warned of a sharp revenue decline as rooftop solar installations slowed dramatically following the rollback of California's net metering policy.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Enphase Energy", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s241", "text": "Shares of First Solar surged after the Treasury Department confirmed that its domestically manufactured panels would qualify for the full 30 percent investment tax credit under the Inflation Reduction Act.", "extractions": [{"entity": "First Solar", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Legal"}, {"entity": "Treasury Department", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "0", "category": "Legal"}]}
{"id": "s242", "text": "Rivian and Lucid Motors both warned they could run out of cash within twelve months unless they secured additional financing, rattling investors in the EV startup sector.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Rivian", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Lucid Motors", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s243", "text": "Li Auto reported record quarterly deliveries, overtaking Nio and Xpeng to become China's best-selling premium electric vehicle brand.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Li Auto", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Nio", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Xpeng", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s244", "text": "Volkswagen's Porsche division reported its operating margin fell below 15 percent for the first time in five years, missing the brand's long-held profitability target.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Volkswagen", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Porsche", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s245", "text": "Stellantis warned of a sharp profit decline after its North American dealers reported record inventory levels, forcing the automaker to offer significant incentives to clear unsold vehicles.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Stellantis", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s246", "text": "Hyundai Motor and Kia reported combined global sales surpassed those of Volkswagen Group for the first time, marking a historic shift in the global automotive rankings.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Hyundai Motor", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Kia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Volkswagen Group", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s247", "text": "Target's quarterly profit collapsed after it was forced to write down 1.5 billion dollars of excess inventory accumulated during a post-pandemic demand miscalculation.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Target", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s248", "text": "Costco reported same-store sales growth of 6.5 percent, outperforming both Walmart and Target as its membership model continued to attract value-conscious consumers.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Costco", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Walmart", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Target", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s249", "text": "Dollar General cut its full-year outlook as its core low-income customer base reduced discretionary spending amid persistent inflation and depleted savings.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Dollar General", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s250", "text": "Estee Lauder cut its dividend and replaced its chief executive after organic sales fell for the sixth consecutive quarter, driven by weak demand in Asia travel retail.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Estee Lauder", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s251", "text": "Nike lost a key endorsement deal with basketball star Ja Morant to rival Puma following a high-profile conduct controversy involving the athlete.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nike", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Puma", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Recruitment"}, {"entity": "Ja Morant", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "~", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s252", "text": "Adidas reported a return to profitability after successfully selling off most of its remaining Yeezy inventory following the termination of its partnership with Ye.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Adidas", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Yeezy", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Ye", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "0", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s253", "text": "Lululemon missed revenue estimates and cut guidance after its chief product officer resigned, raising concerns about slowing innovation in its core women's apparel category.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Lululemon", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s254", "text": "Marriott International raised its full-year revenue per available room forecast as leisure travel demand remained resilient and business travel continued its recovery.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Marriott International", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s255", "text": "Hilton Worldwide reported record hotel occupancy rates globally while Hyatt Hotels warned of softening demand in its luxury resort segment.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Hilton Worldwide", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Hyatt Hotels", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s256", "text": "Booking Holdings gained market share from Expedia as its Genius loyalty program drove stronger customer retention and repeat booking rates.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Booking Holdings", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Expedia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s257", "text": "Warner Bros Discovery reported a 9.1 billion dollar goodwill impairment charge related to its linear television networks, reflecting the accelerating decline of traditional cable.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Warner Bros Discovery", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s258", "text": "Comcast lost more video subscribers than any quarter in its history as cord-cutting accelerated, though its broadband and theme park divisions partially offset the decline.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Comcast", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s259", "text": "T-Mobile gained postpaid phone subscribers for the thirteenth consecutive quarter at the expense of AT&T and Verizon, widening its lead as the fastest-growing US wireless carrier.", "extractions": [{"entity": "T-Mobile", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "AT&T", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "Verizon", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s260", "text": "Charter Communications and Cox Communications announced a merger to create the largest US cable operator by subscribers, challenging Comcast's market leadership.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Charter Communications", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Cox Communications", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Comcast", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s261", "text": "Also weighing on semiconductor stocks was news that TSMC had quietly reduced orders from ASML for its next-generation high-NA EUV machines, suggesting a softer than expected demand outlook.", "extractions": [{"entity": "TSMC", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "ASML", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "high-NA EUV", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s262", "text": "Shares of Arm rallied after Apple confirmed it would use Arm's latest v9 architecture in its next generation of Mac processors, while Intel's share of the laptop market fell to a record low.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Arm", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Apple", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Intel", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s263", "text": "The enterprise software company beat earnings but its stock fell after management warned that customers were taking longer to sign new contracts due to budget scrutiny, while its smaller rival reported accelerating growth.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the enterprise software company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its smaller rival", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s264", "text": "The Chinese EV maker reported its first monthly sales figure exceeding 50,000 units, overtaking both its domestic rivals and the American incumbent in the premium segment.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Chinese EV maker", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its domestic rivals", "entity_type": "OTHER", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "the American incumbent", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s265", "text": "The activist investor disclosed a stake in the media conglomerate and publicly called for the separation of its studio and streaming assets from its legacy broadcast and cable networks.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the activist investor", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "the media conglomerate", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "~", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s266", "text": "The online travel platform reported record gross bookings as its marketing efficiency improved, taking share from its larger rival which had cut its advertising budget.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the online travel platform", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Performance"}, {"entity": "its larger rival", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s267", "text": "The cloud database provider lost its co-founder and long-serving chief executive to retirement, triggering a sharp share price decline as investors worried about strategic continuity.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the cloud database provider", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Recruitment"}]}
{"id": "s268", "text": "The fast food chain reported its worst same-store sales decline in a decade after a food safety incident linked to its supply chain triggered a nationwide consumer boycott.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the fast food chain", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Performance"}]}
{"id": "s269", "text": "The Japanese semiconductor company announced a partnership with a US chip designer to develop next-generation power management chips for electric vehicles, challenging Texas Instruments in the automotive market.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the Japanese semiconductor company", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "a US chip designer", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Texas Instruments", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "-", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s270", "text": "The South Korean conglomerate announced it would invest 300 billion dollars in semiconductors, displays, and biopharmaceuticals over the next five years, its largest ever capital commitment.", "extractions": [{"entity": "the South Korean conglomerate", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
{"id": "s271", "text": "Nvidia's CEO Jensen Huang announced a 500 billion dollar AI infrastructure investment commitment in the United States, made alongside announcements from Microsoft, Google, and SoftBank.", "extractions": [{"entity": "Nvidia", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Jensen Huang", "entity_type": "PERSON", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Microsoft", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "Google", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}, {"entity": "SoftBank", "entity_type": "ORG", "polarity": "+", "category": "Business"}]}
